<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ruchi on Garbh-Ini</title>
    <link>/authors/ruchi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ruchi on Garbh-Ini</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	    <atom:link href="/authors/ruchi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/gruchi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/gruchi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[biography] :
Cutting edge expertise in drug discovery area with a detailed understanding of disease biology utilizing basic science as well as applied biochemistry,cell &amp;amp; molecularbiology and organic chemistry. Worked with leading pharma companies of India and international repute such as Daiichi Sankyo, Ranbaxy and Torrent. Led and managed the global research portfolio managing programs from early discovery to preclinical development for complex human diseases related to inflammation &amp;amp; immunology,respiratory and metabolic disorders utilizing the small molecule,herbal nutraceutical and biologics approaches.
 *  PhD (Immunomodulatory Peptides) CDRI, Lucknow, India, 1997&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Postdoctoral Research Associate, National Institute of Immunology, New Delhi,         India, 1997-2000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Postdoctoral Research Associate, Wayne State University, MI, USA, 2000-2002&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drug Discovery Research (Metabolic diseases, Oncology and Autoimmune disorders,       while working with leading Indian &amp;amp; multinational Pharma companies such as Torrent     Research Centre, Ranbaxy Research Laboratories and Daiichi Sankyo Pharma),            2002-2017&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clinical Research Course and Certification, Anovus Institute of Clinical Research     &amp;amp; Punjab Technical University, India, 2014&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previous Affiliation: Assistant Director and Group Head Pharmacology, Daiichi         Sankyo Life Science Research Centre in India, Gurgaon, India&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research interests&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immune cells in pregnancy are actively and specifically recruited to facilitate the  implantation of fetus in mother’s womb and promote a successful pregnancy.Several studies have been conducted by various research groups to identify the specific immunological patterns in pregnancy which are essential for a normal term birth of infant. An alteration in one or more of these components however, may lead to adverse outcomes of pregnancy such as IUGR, preterm birth and stillbirth.My current research interest is to conduct specific mechanistic studies to decipher the immunological patterns related to feto-maternal tolerance in predicting adverse of pregnancy and use of nutraceuticals to boost the feto-maternal tolerance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also interested in conducting the immunological and metabolite profiling of biological samples from the Garbhini cohort to understand the biology of stillbirth cases utilizing the transcriptome, metabolome and microbiome approaches.Specific mechanistic studies based on above would lead us to understand the role of nutraceuticals to avoid/reduce the cases of still birth in India.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
