<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ARINDAM MAITRA on Garbh-Ini</title>
    <link>/authors/arindam-maitra/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ARINDAM MAITRA on Garbh-Ini</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	    <atom:link href="/authors/arindam-maitra/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/earindam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/earindam/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;[Biography]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have undertaken my doctoral research on genomic diversity of HIV-1 in India in the All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi. Subsequently, I have been engaged as Technical Support Scientist in Applied Biosystems as a member of European Task Forces on high throughput sequencing, gene expression, genotyping and forensic DNA analysis. Subsequently, I have also been Group Leader of Genomics in The Centre for Genomic Application (TCGA), New Delhi and Head of Functional Genomics in Thrombosis Research Institute, Bengaluru. Presently, I am an Associate Professor in National Institute of Biomedical Genomics. I am also the Coordinator of Core Technologies Research Initiative of NIBMG, Project Coordinator of the International Cancer Genome Consortium – India Project at NIBMG, Adjunct Faculty of Regional Centre for Biotechnology and Guest Lecturer of Department of Biochemistry, University of Calcutta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Research Interest&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My research mission is to harness genomics to uncover important and novel information on human health and disease. The emergence of techniques like massively parallel DNA sequencing methods (MPS) has revolutionized our ability to identify causal genomic variants in various human health conditions. Exome and whole genome sequencing based approaches have already been shown to be successful in uncovering the genetic basis of multiple diseases. My aim is to harness emerging technologies like MPS to identify the genetic basis of causality of diseases with special emphasis on preterm birth and cancer. The ultimate purpose of undertaking such work is to discover important genetic information which can be used to identify actionable targets to improve human health.
Institute web page link
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nibmg.ac.in/?q=content/am1-research&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.nibmg.ac.in/?q=content/am1-research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sub study
Stress outcomes on pregnancy and fetal growth: Development of methods to identify mothers at risk of preterm birth and intrauterine growth restriction resulting from maternal stress&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Arindam Maitra (NIBMG) Nitya Wadhwa (THSTI) &amp;amp; Tushar K. Maiti (RCB)
The goals of our study are to contribute to the understanding of the causes of adverse pregnancy outcomes and to find handles to ameliorate these outcomes. In particular, we shall test the hypothesis that sustained stress during pregnancy is a major contributor to adverse pregnancy outcomes. Our objective is to identify biological markers of stress during pregnancy that correlate with enhanced risk of adverse outcomes in mothers and their babies. Once identified, such at-risk mothers can be subjected to specific antenatal stress control programs aimed to eliminate or reduce stress during pregnancy. We are measuring stress by a cross-culturally validated psychological instrument (A-Z Score) and biologically by assaying for telomere length, DNA methylation alterations, levels of hair shaft cortisol and by proteomic analysis in mothers at two time points during pregnancy. This study has been funded by the Grand Challenge India – All Children Thriving Program.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
