<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>partha on Garbh-Ini</title>
    <link>/authors/partha/</link>
    <description>Recent content in partha on Garbh-Ini</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	    <atom:link href="/authors/partha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/cpartha/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/cpartha/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;biography&#34;&gt;Biography&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor Partha Pratim Majumder has completed his PhD from the Indian Statistical Institute, Kolkata. In the course of his extensive and distinguished academic career, he has served in various positions in University of Texas, Indian Statistical Institute, University of Pittsburgh, Jawaharlal Nehru Centre for Advanced Scientific Research and Indian Institute of Science Education &amp;amp; Research. He was the Founder Director of the TCG-ISI Centre for Population Genomics, and also of the National Institute of Biomedical Genomics. Presently, he is a Distinguished Professor at NIBMG, Emeritus Professor at Indian Statistical Institute, Adjunct Professor of the Translational Health Science &amp;amp; Technology Institute and Regional Centre for Biotechnology.  He is currently the President of the Indian Academy of Sciences and the West Bengal Academy of Science &amp;amp; Technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-interest&#34;&gt;Research Interest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human Genome Variation: I am interested in reconstruction of human movements using genomic data, inferring genetic structures of population groups and admixtures among them, and using these inferences to understand genetic epijdemiolgy of disease.
Statistical Genomics: I am interested in developing statistical methodologies and applying statistical methods in genetics.
Genetics and Genomics of Disease:  I am interested in drawing inferences on genetic bases of human diseases and adverse life events using data on families, relative pairs and unrelated individuals.  My current focus is on cancer and pre-term birth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nibmg.ac.in/?q=content/ppm1-research&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Institute web page link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
