<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Garbh-Ini</title>
    <link>/authors/dinkar/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Garbh-Ini</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	    <atom:link href="/authors/dinkar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/bhatnagar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/bhatnagar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PROF. SHINJINI BHATNAGAR, PhD
Dean (clinical Research), Head-pbc, Coordinator-cbd
+91-129-2876351  (+91-129-2876351)
shinjini.bhatnagar@thsti.res.in
Ph.D. (Pediatrics), All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi
Diplomate National Board, All India Institute of Medical Sciences, New Delhi
MBBS, Lady Hardinge Medical College, University of Delhi&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/dinkar/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/authors/dinkar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dinakar M. Salunke :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Karnataka University, Dharwad, India, BSc (Physics, Mathematics and Statistics), 1976 Karnataka University, Dharwad, India, MSc (Physics), 1978
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indian Institute of Science (IISc), Bangalore, India, PhD, 1983
Brandeis University, Waltham, Massachusetts, USA Postdoc, 1988&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scientific Activity :&lt;br /&gt;
                      Understanding the physiological processes of self-nonself discrimination in terms of physicochemical principles of molecular interactions has been a major focus of our research. Our work on the pluripotency of primary immune response led to discovering new ways of antibody degeneracy and has impacted the evolving paradigm shift in immune recognition and generation of antibody repertoire [Immunity (2006) 24:359]. We have analyzed how immune system reacts when encountered with the antigens that keep changing shape and showed that the restricted paratope conformational repertoire on binding of an antigen to multiple independent antibodies may be relevant for minimizing possibility of selfreactive antibodies. Molecular insights into the functional mimicry in the context of immune response were addressed using structural, immunological and thermodynamic approaches. We have demonstrated how paratope plasticity facilitates molecular mimicry of otherwise unrelated antigens. While our analyses of carbohydrate-peptide mimicry provided important conceptual leads towards design and development of new generation of vaccines, the analyses involving carbohydrate-porphyrin mimicry provided possible mechanistic understanding of the molecular pathology of porphyria. Structural issues pertaining to innate immunity and food allergies are also being addressed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
